<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A true and perfect account of the proceedings of the General Sessions of the Peace, holden for London and Middlesex, upon the 15 and 16 of January instant, or, The tryals, examination and confession of the woman that burned her child, and the bayliff that killed another of his fellow bayliffs at Soehoe ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace (London)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1674</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A63423</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T2521</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R21669</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12226657</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12226657</idno>
            <idno type="VID">56564</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A63423)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 56564)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 617:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A true and perfect account of the proceedings of the General Sessions of the Peace, holden for London and Middlesex, upon the 15 and 16 of January instant, or, The tryals, examination and confession of the woman that burned her child, and the bayliff that killed another of his fellow bayliffs at Soehoe ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace (London)</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Court of Quarter Sessions of the Peace (Middlesex)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1674.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: p. 2-3 lacking.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Union Theological Seminary Library, New York.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Trials (Murder) --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:56564:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:56564:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A True and Perfect ACCOUNT OF THE Proceedings at the General Seſſions of the Peace, holden for London and Middleſex, Upon the 15. and 16. of <hi>January</hi> Inſtant.</p>
            <p>OR THE Tryals, Examination and Confeſſion of the Woman that Burned her Child, and the Bayliff that Killed another of his Fellow Bayliffs at <hi>Soehoe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>WITH The Tryals of the Merchants Prentice, who Robb'd his Maſter, and his Maſters Brother, of the Value of 3210.</p>
            <p>Alſo a True Account of the Number of Perſons that are Condemned to Suffer at <hi>Tyburn,</hi> and how many Whipt at the Carts Arſe.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the 1674.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:56564:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:56564:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>A True and Perfect Narrative of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings at the General Seſſion of the Peace holden for <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middleſex,</hi> upon the 15th and 16th of <hi>January</hi> inſtant.</head>
            <p>IT would be neither eaſy to the Wrighter, nor very ſatisfactory to the readers of theſe remar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ques, to have a preciſe account given of every par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular buſineſs at the Seſſions, in every of which, are tryed ſo many Petty felonies, and other common offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces as would be little worth the obſervation of thoſe that ſhould read them, the objects of mens curioſityes being things rare and portentous, and not common and Vulgar; I ſhall therefore pretermit (in this narative) thoſe tryalls that were of leſs note, and conſequence and only give you an account of thoſe that were moſt remarkable at this Seſſions.</p>
            <p>And they were in three notorious miſchances, firſt of a Barbarous Murther acted by an unnatural Mother upon her own Child. 2. for a Villanous Robery <gap reason="missing" extent="2 pages">
                  <desc>〈2 pages missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:56564:3"/>he was ſo much a friend to himſelf as to put himſelf upon his Tryal by Pleading not Guilty.</p>
            <p>Upon his Tryal upon this Second Indictment it was proved againſt him by the Atteſtation of Several VVit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes, that Mr. <hi>Rowland Lee</hi> the Younger Sojourning in his Fathers houſe and heving a Little Room therein for the keeping of his account, the Priſoner being then Servant to his Father took his opportunity when the ſaid Mr. Lee was one day out of Town, broke into the ſaid Room, and thence took a way the aforeſaid 20 Pound.</p>
            <p>The fact was Clearly proved againſt, him both by VVitneſſes and his own confeſſion in a letter of his own wrighting, which was read in Court, and wherein he owned the fact, and ſaid moreover, that he ſtole the key wherewith he opened the door out of the ſaid Mr. <hi>Lees</hi> Pocket; but the witneſſes tonement varyed in their E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidence as to that, whether the ſaid doore was broken open or opened by a key.</p>
            <p>There was ſome diſpute in the Court whither the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictments was well laid for the burglary, for that the fact although the ſame yet related to ſeveral perſons the houſe that was broken open being Mr. <hi>Rowland Lees</hi> the Elder, and the Money that was taken away was Mr. <hi>Rowland Lees</hi> the younger, and therefore it was adviſed whither another Bill ſhould not be drawn up to indict him ſeverally of the burglary, but this Court not being agreed upon; the whole matter was left to the Jury, who brought him in guilty upon
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:56564:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>the firſt Indictment by his own Confeſſons, and upon the Second they at firſt brought him in not guilty, but the Court not being ſatisfied with that Verdict they went out again and brought in a Special Verdict, which is to be argued at another time.</p>
            <p>There was a woman at the ſame time tryed for being acceſſary with the ſaid <hi>Rookewood,</hi> And receiving the monyes that he had Stollen; But although it appeared to the Court that ſhe was a perſon likely enough to be guilty of ſuch a crime, yet no direct Evidence coming in againſt her, ſhe was acquitted.</p>
            <p>The next was one <hi>Edward Coker</hi> who ſtood indicted for the raviſhing of a Child of 11 yeares old, the Child was there and gave her Evidence in Court that the ſaid <hi>Cober</hi> coming into her Aunts houſe where ſhe lived, did get her into a Room and did there force her; The Ant atteſted that ſhe hearing the Child cry out, came into the Room where he was in the dark with her, and found by evident tokens that the Child had bin abuſed, but al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though the fact appreared very foul againſt him yet the Circumſtances thereto not being ſo direct as to prove a Rape, according as the law directs on thoſe caſe, he was brought in not guilty upon that Indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, but that he might not go Scot-free the Court directed another Bill to be drawn up for an Aſſault upon the ſaid Child, which Bill was found, and upon his tryal thereupon was found guilty, and was fined 25 Markes by the Court for his offence.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:56564:4"/>
            <p>There was alſo tryed the Bayliff that killed his fellow Bayliff at <hi>Soehoe,</hi> he was found guilty of Murther.</p>
            <p>The Merchants Servant had the Allowance of his cler<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gy and was burned in the hand, together with 5 other.</p>
            <p>There are Seven men are all condemned to Die whereof the aforeſaid Bayly was one.</p>
            <p>And 8 to be Whipt at the Carts Tayle.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:56564:4"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
